# **AKI GAO**

xiaoyu.akihiro.gao@gmail.com | iknowhtml.github.io | github.com/iknowhtml

### Profile

I am a JavaScript developer with a passion for technology and innovation, in particular the Web and Blockchain. I offer three years of experience in full stack web application development from conception to delivery of elegant and maintainable solutions using functional programming paradigms and test driven development in an Agile environment. My expertise ranges from designing and implementing responsive and user-friendly web-based UX/UIs to architecting and developing modular, scalable and fault-tolerant back end infrastructures. Specifically, I specialize in web application development using the React and Node is ecosystems. I also have experience with Blockchain/DLT technologies, and am actively involved its development and industry.

## Skills

Languages:

JavaScript, TypeScript, Shell (Bash)

UX/UI and Front End Technologies:

Sketch, HTML, CSS, CSS Modules, PostCSS, React, Redux,

Redux-Saga, React Router

Blockchain Technologies:

Solidity, Web3,js, Ethers.js, Truffle, Metamask, Remix

Development and Testing Tools:

Git, Yarn, Webpack, Babel, Mocha, Chai, Sinon, ESlint

Back End and Database Technologies:

Node.js, Express, Redis, RabbitMQ, GraphQL, Apollo,

MongoDB

Infrastructure and DevOps Technologies:

Nginx, Docker, CircleCI, Terraform, Packer, AWS, GCP

# Work Experience

Blockchain Web Application Consultanting - Freelance/Contract Developer

February 2018 - Present

- Provides services to clients to architect and develop front end and back end applications for Blockchain-based platforms, as well as deployment to cloud.
- Also provides consultations to determine viability of Blockchain use cases and conceptualization of decentralized business models based on tokenization and distributed ledgers.
- Specializes in rapid prototyping of performant and user-friendly front end applications to interface with Blockchain back ends, as well as scalable hybrid back end solutions that utilize both traditional database systems and Blockchain.

Alluminate - Javascript & Blockchain Developer

October 2017 - February 2018

- Provide high-level technology expertise and development capabilities for in-house and consulting work ranging from UX/UI to smart contract development.
- Designed, developed and maintained the company's homepage as well as the landing page for several products.
- Core development member of the CryptoPets platform, an Ethereum-based game platform for collecting and battling digital pets developed in partnership with Arcade Distillery.
- Aided in smart contract design, as well as audited smart contracts for correctness.
- Developed in-house development and testing environment using Web3, Docker and Geth.

### Booz Allen Hamilton - Technologist

May 2017 - November 2017

- Developed proof of concept Blockchain applications using Ethereum for various government organizations, including the U.S. Treasury and the FDA.
- Worked across the stack from UX/UI design to implemention of front end and back end logic in React and Node respectively, as well as application deployment to various cloud providers including AWS and Azure in an Agile environment using Kanban.
- Acted as defacto Product Owner and Scrum Master when necessary to translate requirements from the stakeholder, and convert requirements into tasks to be distributed among team members.
- Participation, expertise and leadership in projects led to conversion of one project from a Proof of Concept work into a full-fledged proposal for a contract bid.

### Education

The University of Virginia: School of Engineering and Applied Science (SEAS)

August 2016

• Computer Engineering & Electrical Engineering